<?xml version="1.0" ?><message:Structure xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns:message="http://www.sdmx.org/resources/sdmxml/schemas/v3_0/message" xmlns:str="http://www.sdmx.org/resources/sdmxml/schemas/v3_0/structure" xmlns:com="http://www.sdmx.org/resources/sdmxml/schemas/v3_0/common"><message:Header><message:ID>IREF427848</message:ID><message:Test>false</message:Test><message:Prepared>2025-02-21T12:59:44Z</message:Prepared><message:Sender id="Unknown"></message:Sender><message:Receiver id="not_supplied"></message:Receiver></message:Header><message:Structures><str:Codelists><str:Codelist urn="urn:sdmx:org.sdmx.infomodel.codelist.Codelist=SDMX:CL_CIVIL_STATUS(1.0)" isExternalReference="false" agencyID="SDMX" id="CL_CIVIL_STATUS" version="1.0"><com:Name xml:lang="en">Civil (or Marital) Status</com:Name><com:Description xml:lang="en">This code list provides a list of values for describing the civil (or marital) status of an individual, i.e. the legal, conjugal status of an individual in relation to the marriage laws or customs of the country. This code list was formally adopted on 25 November 2013. More information about this code list and SDMX code lists in general (e.g. list of generic codes for expressing general concepts like "Total", "Unknown", etc.; syntaxes for the creation of further codes; general guidelines for the creation of SDMX code lists) can be found at this address: https://sdmx.org/?page_id=4345.</com:Description><str:Code urn="urn:sdmx:org.sdmx.infomodel.codelist.Code=SDMX:CL_CIVIL_STATUS(1.0).S" id="S"><com:Name xml:lang="en">Single person</com:Name><com:Description xml:lang="en">This code includes persons who have never been married or in registered partnership.</com:Description></str:Code><str:Code urn="urn:sdmx:org.sdmx.infomodel.codelist.Code=SDMX:CL_CIVIL_STATUS(1.0).M" id="M"><com:Name xml:lang="en">Married person</com:Name><com:Description xml:lang="en">This code covers both persons living in a same-sex marriage as well as in an opposite-sex marriage. This code excludes legally separated persons.</com:Description></str:Code><str:Code urn="urn:sdmx:org.sdmx.infomodel.codelist.Code=SDMX:CL_CIVIL_STATUS(1.0).W" id="W"><com:Name xml:lang="en">Widowed person</com:Name><com:Description xml:lang="en">This code includes persons whose marriage ended with the death of the partner and who are not remarried or in a registered partnership.</com:Description></str:Code><str:Code urn="urn:sdmx:org.sdmx.infomodel.codelist.Code=SDMX:CL_CIVIL_STATUS(1.0).D" id="D"><com:Name xml:lang="en">Divorced person</com:Name><com:Description xml:lang="en">This code includes persons whose marriage ended with a divorce procedure and who are not remarried or in a registered partnership.</com:Description></str:Code><str:Code urn="urn:sdmx:org.sdmx.infomodel.codelist.Code=SDMX:CL_CIVIL_STATUS(1.0).L" id="L"><com:Name xml:lang="en">Legally separated person</com:Name><com:Description xml:lang="en">This code includes persons who are separated: they are still married, but "officially" separated.</com:Description></str:Code><str:Code urn="urn:sdmx:org.sdmx.infomodel.codelist.Code=SDMX:CL_CIVIL_STATUS(1.0).P" id="P"><com:Name xml:lang="en">Person in registered partnership</com:Name><com:Description xml:lang="en">This code covers both persons living in an opposite-sex registered partnership as well as in a same-sex registered partnership. Registered partnerships also include customary unions that are legal and binding under national law. This code excludes persons whose registered partnership was legally dissolved.</com:Description></str:Code><str:Code urn="urn:sdmx:org.sdmx.infomodel.codelist.Code=SDMX:CL_CIVIL_STATUS(1.0).Q" id="Q"><com:Name xml:lang="en">Person whose registered partnership ended with the death of the partner</com:Name><com:Description xml:lang="en">This code includes persons whose registered partnership ended with the death of the partner and who are not remarried or in a registered partnership.</com:Description></str:Code><str:Code urn="urn:sdmx:org.sdmx.infomodel.codelist.Code=SDMX:CL_CIVIL_STATUS(1.0).E" id="E"><com:Name xml:lang="en">Person whose registered partnership was legally dissolved</com:Name><com:Description xml:lang="en">This code includes persons whose registered partnership ended with a legal procedure and who are not remarried or in a registered partnership.</com:Description></str:Code></str:Codelist></str:Codelists></message:Structures></message:Structure>