<?xml version="1.0" ?><message:Structure xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns:message="http://www.sdmx.org/resources/sdmxml/schemas/v3_0/message" xmlns:str="http://www.sdmx.org/resources/sdmxml/schemas/v3_0/structure" xmlns:com="http://www.sdmx.org/resources/sdmxml/schemas/v3_0/common"><message:Header><message:ID>IREF427914</message:ID><message:Test>false</message:Test><message:Prepared>2025-02-21T12:59:55Z</message:Prepared><message:Sender id="Unknown"></message:Sender><message:Receiver id="not_supplied"></message:Receiver></message:Header><message:Structures><str:Codelists><str:Codelist urn="urn:sdmx:org.sdmx.infomodel.codelist.Codelist=SDMX:CL_OBS_STATUS(2.2)" isExternalReference="false" agencyID="SDMX" id="CL_OBS_STATUS" version="2.2"><com:Name xml:lang="en">Observation Status</com:Name><str:Code urn="urn:sdmx:org.sdmx.infomodel.codelist.Code=SDMX:CL_OBS_STATUS(2.2).A" id="A"><com:Name xml:lang="en">Normal value</com:Name><com:Description xml:lang="en">To be used as default value if no value is provided or when no special coded qualification is assumed. Usually, it can be assumed that the source agency assigns sufficient confidence to the provided observation and/or the value is not expected to be dramatically revised.</com:Description></str:Code><str:Code urn="urn:sdmx:org.sdmx.infomodel.codelist.Code=SDMX:CL_OBS_STATUS(2.2).B" id="B"><com:Name xml:lang="en">Time series break</com:Name><com:Description xml:lang="en">Observations are characterised as such when different content exists or a different methodology has been applied to this observation as compared with the preceding one (the one given for the previous period).</com:Description></str:Code><str:Code urn="urn:sdmx:org.sdmx.infomodel.codelist.Code=SDMX:CL_OBS_STATUS(2.2).D" id="D"><com:Name xml:lang="en">Definition differs</com:Name><com:Description xml:lang="en">Used to indicate slight deviations from the established methodology (footnote-type information); these divergences do not imply a break in time series.</com:Description></str:Code><str:Code urn="urn:sdmx:org.sdmx.infomodel.codelist.Code=SDMX:CL_OBS_STATUS(2.2).E" id="E"><com:Name xml:lang="en">Estimated value</com:Name><com:Description xml:lang="en">Observation obtained through an estimation methodology (e.g. to produce back-casts) or based on the use of a limited amount of data or ad hoc sampling and through additional calculations (e.g. to produce a value at an early stage of the production stage while not all data are available). It may also be used in case of experimental data (e.g. in the context of a pilot ahead of a full scale production process) or in case of data of (anticipated/assessed) low quality. If needed, additional information can be provided through free text using the COMMENT_OBS attribute at the observation level or at a higher level. This code is to be used when the estimation is done by a sender agency. When the imputation is carried out by a receiver agency in order to replace or fill gaps in reported data series, the flag to use is I "Value imputed by a receiving agency".</com:Description></str:Code><str:Code urn="urn:sdmx:org.sdmx.infomodel.codelist.Code=SDMX:CL_OBS_STATUS(2.2).F" id="F"><com:Name xml:lang="en">Forecast value</com:Name><com:Description xml:lang="en">Value deemed to assess the magnitude which a quantity will assume at some future point of time (as distinct from "estimated value" which attempts to assess the magnitude of an already existent quantity).</com:Description></str:Code><str:Code urn="urn:sdmx:org.sdmx.infomodel.codelist.Code=SDMX:CL_OBS_STATUS(2.2).G" id="G"><com:Name xml:lang="en">Experimental value</com:Name><com:Description xml:lang="en">Data collected on the basis of definitions or (alternative) collection methods under development. Data not of guaranteed quality as normally expected from provider.</com:Description></str:Code><str:Code urn="urn:sdmx:org.sdmx.infomodel.codelist.Code=SDMX:CL_OBS_STATUS(2.2).I" id="I"><com:Name xml:lang="en">Value imputed by a receiving agency</com:Name><com:Description xml:lang="en">Observation imputed by a receiving agency to replace or fill gaps in reported data series. This code is intended to cover all cases where a receiving agency publishes data about a sending agency that do not come from an official source in the sender agency's reporting framework. When the estimation is done by the sender agency, the flag to use is E "Estimated value".</com:Description></str:Code><str:Code urn="urn:sdmx:org.sdmx.infomodel.codelist.Code=SDMX:CL_OBS_STATUS(2.2).K" id="K"><com:Name xml:lang="en">Data included in another category</com:Name><com:Description xml:lang="en">This code is used when data for a given category are missing and are included in another category, sub-total or total. Generally where code "K" is used there should be a corresponding code "W - Includes data from another category" assigned to the over-covered category. Implementers and data reporters should use the COMMENT_OBS observation-level attribute to specify under which category the data are included.</com:Description></str:Code><str:Code urn="urn:sdmx:org.sdmx.infomodel.codelist.Code=SDMX:CL_OBS_STATUS(2.2).W" id="W"><com:Name xml:lang="en">Includes data from another category</com:Name><com:Description xml:lang="en">This code is used when data include another category, or go beyond the scope of the data collection and are therefore over-covered. Generally, where code "W" is used there should be a corresponding code "K - Data included in another category" assigned to the category which is under-covered. Implementers and data reporters should use the COMMENT_OBS observation-level attribute to specify which additional data are included.</com:Description></str:Code><str:Code urn="urn:sdmx:org.sdmx.infomodel.codelist.Code=SDMX:CL_OBS_STATUS(2.2).O" id="O"><com:Name xml:lang="en">Missing value</com:Name><com:Description xml:lang="en">This code is to be used when no breakdown is made between the reasons why data are missing. Data can be missing due to many reasons: data cannot exist, data exist but are not collected (e.g. because they are below a certain threshold or subject to a derogation clause), data are unreliable, etc.</com:Description></str:Code><str:Code urn="urn:sdmx:org.sdmx.infomodel.codelist.Code=SDMX:CL_OBS_STATUS(2.2).M" id="M"><com:Name xml:lang="en">Missing value; data cannot exist</com:Name><com:Description xml:lang="en">Used to denote empty cells resulting from the impossibility to collect a statistical value (e.g. a particular education level or type of institution may be not applicable to a given country's education system).</com:Description></str:Code><str:Code urn="urn:sdmx:org.sdmx.infomodel.codelist.Code=SDMX:CL_OBS_STATUS(2.2).P" id="P"><com:Name xml:lang="en">Provisional value</com:Name><com:Description xml:lang="en">An observation is characterised as "provisional" when the source agency - while it bases its calculations on its standard production methodology - considers that the data, almost certainly, are expected to be revised.</com:Description></str:Code><str:Code urn="urn:sdmx:org.sdmx.infomodel.codelist.Code=SDMX:CL_OBS_STATUS(2.2).S" id="S"><com:Name xml:lang="en">Strike and other special events</com:Name><com:Description xml:lang="en">Special circumstances (e.g. strike) affecting the observation or causing a missing value.</com:Description></str:Code><str:Code urn="urn:sdmx:org.sdmx.infomodel.codelist.Code=SDMX:CL_OBS_STATUS(2.2).L" id="L"><com:Name xml:lang="en">Missing value; data exist but were not collected</com:Name><com:Description xml:lang="en">Used, for example, when some data are not reported/disseminated because they are below a certain threshold.</com:Description></str:Code><str:Code urn="urn:sdmx:org.sdmx.infomodel.codelist.Code=SDMX:CL_OBS_STATUS(2.2).H" id="H"><com:Name xml:lang="en">Missing value; holiday or weekend</com:Name><com:Description xml:lang="en">Used in some daily data flows.</com:Description></str:Code><str:Code urn="urn:sdmx:org.sdmx.infomodel.codelist.Code=SDMX:CL_OBS_STATUS(2.2).Q" id="Q"><com:Name xml:lang="en">Missing value; suppressed</com:Name><com:Description xml:lang="en">Used, for example, when data are suppressed due to statistical confidentiality considerations.</com:Description></str:Code><str:Code urn="urn:sdmx:org.sdmx.infomodel.codelist.Code=SDMX:CL_OBS_STATUS(2.2).J" id="J"><com:Name xml:lang="en">Derogation</com:Name><com:Description xml:lang="en">Clause in an agreement (e.g. legal act, gentlemen's agreement) stating that some provisions in the agreement are not to be implemented by designated parties; these derogations may affect the observation or cause a missing value. In general, derogations are limited in time.</com:Description></str:Code><str:Code urn="urn:sdmx:org.sdmx.infomodel.codelist.Code=SDMX:CL_OBS_STATUS(2.2).N" id="N"><com:Name xml:lang="en">Not significant</com:Name><com:Description xml:lang="en">Used to indicate a value which is not a "real" zero (e.g. a result of 0.0004 rounded to zero).</com:Description></str:Code><str:Code urn="urn:sdmx:org.sdmx.infomodel.codelist.Code=SDMX:CL_OBS_STATUS(2.2).U" id="U"><com:Name xml:lang="en">Low reliability</com:Name><com:Description xml:lang="en">This indicates existing observations, but for which the user should also be aware of the low quality assigned.</com:Description></str:Code><str:Code urn="urn:sdmx:org.sdmx.infomodel.codelist.Code=SDMX:CL_OBS_STATUS(2.2).V" id="V"><com:Name xml:lang="en">Unvalidated value</com:Name><com:Description xml:lang="en">Observation as received from the respondent without further evaluation of data quality.</com:Description></str:Code></str:Codelist></str:Codelists></message:Structures></message:Structure>